Leser, Paul; Papers ger058
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) Lingemann Collection, 1913-1964; 4; 6 cubic ft. 353 file folders
  - Correspondence with others, 4.27
    - Dougill, Vera, 1948-1949 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 42)
    - Dreifuß, Julius, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 43)
    - Drost, H., 1949 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 44)
    - Dücker, Carl, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 45)
    - Erhard, Hans, 1947-1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 46)
    - Everling, Friedrich, 1947-1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 47)
    - Feisenberger, Ewing, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 48)
    - Frey, Erwin R., 1948; 1951 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 49)
    - Friedrich, Walter, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 50)
    - Gemeinschaft der rassisch und politisch verfolgten Christen e.V., 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 51)
    - Gesellschaft für Christlich-Jüdische Zusammenarbeit in Bonn e.V., 1955 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 52)
    - Gippert, Pastor, 1952 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 53)
    - Gockeln, Oberbürgermeister, 1949 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 54)
    - Gottsmann, Walther, 1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 55)
    - Greinert, Ministerialrat, 1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 56)
    - Grimme, Adolf, 1955 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 57)
    - Grünhut, Max, 1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 58)
    - Hagemann, Max, 1948; 1955 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 59)
    - Hammerschlag, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 60)
    - Hauptwald, R., 1955 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 61)
    - Heinemann, Hans, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 62)
    - Hemer, Heinrich, 1947-1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 63)
    - Hemken, Ruth, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 64)
    - Hermes, Anna, 1960 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 65)
    - Heydrich, M., 1960 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 66)
    - Hippel, Ernst von, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 67)
    - Hoberg, 1955 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 68)
    - Hopmann, Heinrich, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 69)
    - Jewish Committee for Relief Abroad, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 70)
    - Jüttner, Ignaz, 1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 71)
    - Keimer, Ernst, Undated (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 72)
    - Kesseböhmer, 1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 73)
    - Kiesselbach, W., 1947-1949 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 74)
    - Kirchner, 1948-1949 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 75)
    - Koch, Ekhard, 1947-1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 76)
    - Kohlhaas, Max, 1954-1955 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 77)
    - Konrad, Anton, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 78)
    - Kost, Heinrich, 1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 79)
    - Kuhnt, G., 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 80)
    - Liesegang, Albert, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 81)
    - Linz, 1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 82)
    - Lüders, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 83)
    - Macaskie, N. L., 1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 84)
    - Marek, Christa, 1956; 1957 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 85)
    - Merrick, W., 1948 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 86)
    - Moehlen, Adolf Stier tom, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 87)
    - Mörike, 1947 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 88)
    - Moldenhauer, Margarete, 1953 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 89)
    - Moller, N. H., 1948-1949 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 90)
    - Muthesius, 1951 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 91)
    - Die Neue Zeitung, 1946 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 92)
    - Neuhaus, Carl M., 1960 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 93)
    - Neukamp, Franz, 1946 (Box 18 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 94)
    - Neumann, Richard, 1954 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 1)
    - Niemeyer, Gerda, 1955 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 2)
    - Niethammer, Emil, 1947-1948; 1954-1955 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 3)
    - Niethammer, Emil, 80th birthday celebration, Undated (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 4)
    - Niethammer, Emil, 85th birthday celebration, Undated (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 5)
    - Orth, Hermann, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 6)
    - Passmore, Douglas G., 1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 7)
    - Pastor, Wilhelm L., 1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 8)
    - Peters, Karl, 1947; 1953 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 9)
    - Profitlich, Anni, 1945 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 10)
    - Pütz, Leopold, 1945 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 11)
    - Quaas, Friedrich, 1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 12)
    - Rahaus, Albert, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 13)
    - Rathbone, J. F. W., 1946-1949 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 14)
    - Richter, Elisabeth, 1954 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 15)
    - Rinck, Gerd, 1954 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 16)
    - Rintelen, 1945 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 17)
    - Rotberg, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 18)
    - Rothfels, Brigitte, 1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 19)
    - Saarbach, W. E., 1948; 1949 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 20)
    - Saller, K., 1953 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 21)
    - Schanz, Agnes, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 22)
    - Schetter, M., 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 23)
    - Schiffer, Karl, 1953 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 24)
    - Schilling, Joseph, 1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 25)
    - Schmidt, Johannes, 1947; 1953 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 26)
    - Schmidt-Thomé, Franz, 1952 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 27)
    - Schneidewin, Karl, 1954 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 28)
    - Schönke, Adolf, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 29)
    - Schulte, Hubertus, 1953 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 30)
    - Schulz, Werner, 1946-1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 31)
    - Schwenk, Edmund H., 1955; 1957 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 32)
    - Schwering, 1954 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 33)
    - Sethe, Karl, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 34)
    - Söderman, Harry, 1948; 1951 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 35)
    - Spanier, Paul, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 36)
    - Stäcker, Otto, 1946 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 37)
    - Staff, Dr, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 38)
    - Stoltenhoff, D., 1948-1949 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 39)
    - Sträter, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 40)
    - Stück, Hans, 1954 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 41)
    - Universität Köln, Juristische Fakultät, 1945-1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 42)
    - Veith, Hans Joachim, 1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 43)
    - Veltman, Rudolf, 1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 44)
    - Vereinigung der Verfolgten des Naziregimes, 1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 45)
    - Verlag Götz Schwippert, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 46)
    - Vins, Wilhelm, 1946 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 47)
    - Vrij-Ledeboer, G. H., 1955 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 48)
    - Walter de Gruyter & Co., 1947; 1952-1953 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 49)
    - Wandersleb, Hermann, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 50)
    - Wedel, Graf Ernst von, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 51)
    - Weischenberg, Hubert, 1947-1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 52)
    - Westdeutsche Wirtschaftszeitung, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 53)
    - Wiefels, J., 1947-1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 54)
    - Wimmer, August, 1945-1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 55)
    - Wirtz, Carl, 1946 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 56)
    - Wolff, Ernst, 1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 57)
    - Zander, Josef, 1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 58)
    - Zimmermann, Elisabeth; Zimmermann, Otto, 1947-1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 59)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 60)
  - Writings of Heinrich Lingemann, 4.28
    - "Demokratie u. Justiz", (Undated ca. 1947-1948) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 61)
    - "Fünftes Buch. Beteiligung des Verletzten be idem Verfahren", (1953) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 62)
    - "Handels- u. Wechselrecht". Notes, 1901 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 63)
    - "Inwieweit unterliegen heute Staatliche Rechtsvorschriften der Nachprüfung durch die Gerichte?", (1949) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 64)
    - "Neugründung der Rhein.Westfälischen-Gefängnis Gesellschaft durch den Oberlandesgerichtspräsident Lingemann", (Undated) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 65)
    - "Reisebericht", (1945) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 66)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts and typescripts, Undated (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 67)
  - Case files, 4.29
    - Kriegsgefangenenlagern, Undated (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 68)
    - Military government / Militärregierung, Undated (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 69)
    - Reichsvereinigung Textilveredlung, Undated (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 70)
    - Reichsvereinigung Textilveredlung. Publications, 1942-1943 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 71)
    - Reichsvereinigung Textilveredlung. Publications, 1944 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 72)
    - Bader, Lydia (geb. Rantz), 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 73)
    - Bräutigam, Otto / Leibbrandt, Georg, 1949-1950 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 74)
    - Bräutigam, Otto. "Meine Tätigkeit während des Krieges im Auswärtigen Amt, im Ostministerium und im Generalstab des Feldheeres, insbesondere meine Haltung in der Judenfrage". Typescripts, correspondence, 1956 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 75)
    - Bräutigam, Otto. Correspondence with Heinrich Lingemann, 1956-1958 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 76)
    - Bräutigam, Otto. Clippings, Undated (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 77)
    - Gutachten Dr. Bräutigam, Undated (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 78)
    - Herbold, Josef, 1945 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 79)
    - Kipp, Karl Theodor, 1948 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 80)
    - Küppers, Heinrich; Heidenthal, Josef, 1946 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 81)
    - Lenzen, Ludwig, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 82)
    - Schmitz, Maria; Buschmann, Wilhelmine, 1946 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 83)
    - Tillmann, Max, 1947 (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 84)
  - Typescripts by others, 4.30
    - Amelunxen, Dr.; texts of speeches, Undated (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 85)
    - Bauhofer, Arthur; reprint, Undated (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 86)
    - Beemelmans, Feldkriegsgerichtsrat. "Einzelbericht der Sektion III über die Militärstrafrechtspflege zum Gesamtbericht über die Verwaltung der besetzten Gebiete", (1918) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 87)
    - Haensel, Carl. "Die nach Kontrollratsgesetz Nr. 10 strafbare Organisationszuge-hörigkeit als Conspiracy", (1947) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 88)
    - Lange, Richard. "Mittel und Wege zur Überwindung der deutschen Rechtszersplitterung", (1947) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 89)
    - Schmidt, Albert. "Staatsanwaltschaft ohne Voruntersuchung. Stärkung ihrer Stellung", (Undated) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 90)
    - Smend, Julius. Abhandlung über die Krebsbekämpfung, (1946) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 91)
    - Weidemann, Heinrich. "Grundzüge meiner Verteidigung im Falle Watz", (1947) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 92)
    - Wimmer, Senatspräsident Dr. "Das englische Strafverfahren", (1946) (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 93)
    - Nordrhein-Westfalen. Clippings, press releases, Undated (Box 19 (4-Series 4 - Maria (Mira) and Heinrich (Heinz) ), Folder 94)
- Series 5 - General Correspondence, 1913-1984; 5; 16 cubic ft. 1548 file folders
  This is the largest series in the collection and contains Leser's correspondence with other anthropologists and colleagues, life-long friends, as well as some students. (The bulk of the student correspondence is filed with the student records, Series 16).
  Included in the anthropologists and colleagues with whom Leser carried on lengthy correspondences are: Ford L. Battles, Hermann Baumann, Wolfram Becker, Gösta Berg, Martin Block, Branimir Bratanic, Sigurd Erixon, Robert Heine-Geldern, P. Joseph Henninger, Martin Heydrich, Paul Honigsheim, Wilhelm Koppers, Melvin Kranzberg, Johannes Lehmann, Grith Lerche, Géza de Rohan-Csermak, P. Wilhelm Schmidt, Flola Shepard, Else and Hans Staudinger and Axel Steensberg. He also maintained contact with former students over the years, including Margaret Arnott, Gail Cromack, Hubert and Harriett Reynolds and Donald C. Johanson.
  In addition to correspondence with colleagues and students, Paul Leser maintained his contact with former friends, many who remained in Germany and who were involved in the Youth Movement (Jugendbewegung) of the 1920s and 1930s. A number of these contacts spanned five to six decades and included: Eva Bramesfeld, Kurt Hanf-Dressler, Max Hoffmann, Else Homann, Wolf Kaiser, Friedrich (Bibich) Klemm, Willi J. (Knöppchen) Knoob, Gräfin Maria Lanckoronska, Richard (Lo) Lohmann, Heinrich (Heino) Moeller, Hanna (Hannako) and Hermann Pauli, Ernest (Benjo) Zeitel, and the brothers Robert, Bernhard, Karl Oelbermann.
  - Abrahams, Roger, 1963 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Ackeren, Carl van, 1966 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Ackerman, Robert E., 1949-1951 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Adamczyk, Jan, 1957 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Adams, Evan M., 1961 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Adams, John B., 1951; 1955 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Adler, Arthur M., 1951 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Adler, Robert S., 1946-1947 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Aereboe, Friedrich, 1933-1934 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Aginsky, Burt, 1956 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Aigner, Hanna, 1946 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Aitken, Robert, 1954-1965 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Aitken, Barbara, 1965-1966 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Akeley, T. Barton & Margaret (Peggy), 1948-1953; 1962 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Akeley, Frances, Undated (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Akim, Bertha, 1959 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Albert, Ludwig, 1926-1927; 1959-1960 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Albes, Paula, 1948; 1952 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Allen, Francis R., 1961-1962 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Almeida, António de, 1962 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Alpers, Ernst, 1921-1935 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Anderberg, Lisa, 1952 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Andernach, Dietrich, 1976-1979 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Anderson, Edward, 1957-1959 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Anderson, Jay Allan, 1969 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Anderson, Myrdene, 1978-1981 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Anderson, Robert T., 1966 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Andersson, Elisabeth, 1940-1941 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Andersson, Emil, 1948; 1951; 1952 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Andreae, Norah, 1945-1949 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Andrews, Arnold, 1949-1960 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Andriolo, Karin R., 1980-1981 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Angel, J. Lawrence, 1963 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Ankermann, Bernhard, 1925-1927 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, 1969 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Archer, Raymond L., 1957 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - Arnott, Margaret, 1952-1953 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 35)
    See also file in Series 16, Student records/papers.
  - Arnott, Margaret, 1954 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - Arnott, Margaret, 1955 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 37)
  - Arnott, Margaret, 1956 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 38)
  - Arnott, Margaret, 1957-1958 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 39)
  - Arnott, Margaret, 1959-1961 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Arnott, Margaret, 1962-1965 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 41)
  - Arnott, Margaret, 1966-1968 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 42)
  - Arnott, Margaret, 1969-1971 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 43)
  - Arnott, Margaret, 1972-1977 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 44)
  - Arnott, Margaret, 1978-1984 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 45)
  - Arvefjord, Stig, 1951 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 46)
  - Kristiansson, Gunnar & Marianne, 1951 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 46)
  - Atkin, Adam, 1951 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 47)
  - Atkin, Robert, 1963 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 48)
  - Aubin, Hermann, 1924-1929 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 49)
  - Auerbach, Alfred, 1914; 1946; 1975 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 50)
  - Avitsur, Shmuel, 1971-1975 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 51)
  - Bacon, Elizabeth E., 1963 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 52)
  - Badner, Mino, 1973 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 53)
  - Badt, F., 1934-1936 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 54)
  - Baerwald, H[ans], 1932 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 55)
  - Bahr, Max Dietrich (Fuzzi), 1965-1966 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 56)
  - Bailey, L. Scott, 1961 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 57)
  - Bailey, Moses, 1959; 1967-1983 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 58)
  - Bailey, Paul, 1955 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 59)
  - Baisch, Erwin, 1932 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 60)
  - Baker, Fordyce, 1944-1954 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 61)
  - Balassa, Iván, 1956-1979 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 62)
  - Baldus, Herbert, 1965 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 63)
  - Bandke, Lotte, 1947 (Box 20 (5-Series 5 - General Correspondence), Folder 64)